# **Aleksey Romanov**

I am an experienced front-end developer who is enthusiastic about keeping pace with modern technologies. My passion lies in expanding my knowledge and turning ideas into reality through coding.

For a more in-depth look at additional skills and projects, please visit my **Personal Portfolio Website** or **GitHub**.

Czech Republic, Prague +420 608 190 285 aleksey55121@gmail.com

Portfolio Website
LinkedIn
GitHub

### **SKILLS**

Main: TypeScript, React, Redux, React Native, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Tailwind Other: React Router, Next.js, Vite, Webpack, Zustand, Redux Saga, shadcn/ui, Styled Components, SCSS, Bootstrap, Framer Motion, ESLint, Prettier, Storybook, Figma, Jest, Cypress, Convex, Clerk, Liveblocks, Git, GitLab, Redis, PostgreSQL, PL/pgSQL, OracleDB, PL/SQL, Golang, Docker, Cl/CD, SonarQube, OpenStack, OpenShift, Jira, REST, GraphQL

### **LANGUAGES**

Czech, English, Russian, Ukrainian

## **EDUCATION**

# Faculty of Information Technology CTU, Prague — Bachelor degree

September 2022 - until now

CTU FIT is an institution known for its excellence in technology education. Educational program is Software Engineering.

## **1. Slavic Gymnasium, Prague** — Maturita

September 2018 - June 2022

This gymnasium is a high school focused on providing quality general education.

## **PROJECTS**

## **Collaborative Whiteboard**

This is an application built with React, Next.js, and TypeScript.

In this application, people can sign in with Google, create organizations, invite members to them, create organization whiteboards, and collaborate in real time with other members.

GitHub link: <a href="https://github.com/procellis33/collaboration-whiteboard">https://github.com/procellis33/collaboration-whiteboard</a>

Project showcase: <a href="https://youtu.be/43\_2mJxDjWY">https://youtu.be/43\_2mJxDjWY</a>

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **ЕрмакДом** — Software Engineer

July 2023 - until now

ErmakDom (v2.0) is an internal multi-role application. It includes auth and various roles for construction process management: Administration, Project management, Finance, Supply and Technical supervision.

In this project I:

- designed the application architecture (frontend, backend, databases)
- selected an appropriate database and designed its schema
- selected technologies for frontend and backend
- developed backend and frontend from scratch
- implemented and thought through application and business logic
- maintained open communication with clients throughout the process

This application allows the company to store the history of past and current construction projects, control the construction process, view progress, manage employees, and more. This application is only for internal use by employees.

# ЕрмакДом — Frontend Developer

May 2023 - June 2023

ErmakDom (v1.0) is a local mobile application only for internal use.

In this project I:

- selected technologies for frontend
- developed frontend from scratch
- implemented and thought through application and business logic
- maintained open communication with clients throughout the process

Application allows the company to keep track of construction sites progress.

# **Professional development**

September 2022 - May 2023

I took a break for studies at CTU FIT, where I learned fundamentals such as C, C++, Assembler, computer logic, advanced data structures, efficient data handling and the architecture of computers. Later, I delved into DevOps and different databases.

## **Verdeco** — Frontend Developer

April 2021 - October 2022

Initially, I accumulated experience within the team by completing simple tasks such as adding new components and fixing bugs. Subsequently, I progressed as a frontend developer to handling more challenging assignments, including the creation of crucial components with key logic, refactoring legacy code, optimizing the application, engaging in code reviews, and occasionally participating in technical interviews.

The project had a primary focus on logistics, accounting, and finance.